<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-22T12:45:56-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Katelyn Lemay</title><entry><title type="html">Katelyn Lemay | How to write a resignation letter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/20/resignation-letter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Katelyn Lemay | How to write a resignation letter" /><published>2019-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/20/resignation-letter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/20/resignation-letter.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-write-a-resignation-letter&quot;&gt;How to write a resignation letter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was asked for advice on how to write a resignation letter. I thought I’d share here in case this information is more widely useful. I’ve provided a template along with the actual letter I used when I left my last job (with some sensitive information redacted).
You’ll notice that some of the text on this page is highlighted in yellow— I’ve used a tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.hypothes.is/&quot;&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt; to annotate the template and example letters. Click on the yellow text to open the annotation sidebar and read the attached annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;template&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[DATE OF MEETING WITH MANAGER]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Dear [MANAGER],&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Please accept this letter as formal notification that I am resigning from my position as [JOB TITLE] at [EMPLOYER]. I have accepted a [JOB TITLE] position outside of [EMPLOYER] effective [NEW START DATE]. This means my last day at [EMPLOYER] will be [LAST DAY].&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;As you know, I have been at [EMPLOYER] for [LENGTH OF EMPLOYMENT], having joined the team in [MONTH AND YEAR OF START DATE]. [LIST THINGS YOU’VE ACCOMPLISHED AND LEARNED].&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I’m grateful for [THE OPPORTUNITIES I’VE HAD / THE SUPPORTIVE WORK ENVIRONMENT YOU’VE PROVIDED / SOMETHING NICE], and I [HOPE TO STAY IN TOUCH / LOOK FORWARD TO KEEPING UP WITH THE WORK THAT WILL COME OUT OF THE DEPARTMENT]. In the next [FEW DAYS / TWO WEEKS], I will work with you to ensure projects are wrapped up and department operations are set to continue smoothly after my departure.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[YOUR NAME]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;example&quot;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November 21, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear [Manager name redacted],&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please accept this letter as formal notification that I am resigning from my position as Educational Technology Specialist at the NYU Faculty of Arts &amp;amp; Science Office of Educational Technology. I have accepted a software engineering position outside of NYU, effective January 1, 2018. My last day at NYU will be December 22, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, I have been a full-time employee of NYU for over 5 years, having joined the FAS Office of Ed Tech in January 2016. In the nearly two years of working with this department I have developed new design and technical skills, presented at a conference for the first time, and worked with extraordinary educators on course innovations and enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so grateful for the supportive and encouraging environment you have created in the Office of Ed Tech, and would like you to know that my decision to leave was not an easy one. During my last weeks here, I will of course work with you to ensure my projects are wrapped up or handed off seamlessly, and to transfer ownership of all knowledge, documents, and supplies to you and the rest of the team as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to keep in touch and to hear about all the amazing work I know this department will continue to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katelyn Lemay&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A template resignation letter to help you quit your job gracefully.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://katelynlemay.com/images/opengraph-preview.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Katelyn Lemay | README</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/07/24/README.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Katelyn Lemay | README" /><published>2019-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/07/24/README</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/07/24/README.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-manager-readme&quot;&gt;My Manager README&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.hypothes.is/&quot;&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;, my manager at the time sent &lt;a href=&quot;https://andrew.hedges.name/my-manager-readme.html&quot;&gt;a Manager README&lt;/a&gt; before my first day. It gave me a sense of what it would be like to work with him, and spelled out some expectations that we’re normally required to guess at in the workplace. My README is inspired by and adapted from his— I hope you find this useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in Brooklyn, NY and enjoy traveling. I’m always working to improve my activism and allyship in all areas of social justice. I ﻿like games (of the video and tabletop variety), dogs (please send me pictures of your dog), and talking about language (I ﻿have a BA in Linguistics). ﻿
﻿﻿
You are welcome but not at all obligated to follow and interact with me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lemayke&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/klemay&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.katelynlemay.com/&quot;&gt;my personal website&lt;/a&gt;. ﻿I won’t follow/friend you anywhere unless you tell me it’s OK to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to work with you! As your manager, my primary role will be:﻿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarifying priorities, strategy, and context for the work we do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing appropriate tools and removing barriers to productivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can help with questions you might have about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Benefits, time off, and other logistics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The history behind decisions made before you joined the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Navigating tough conversations with other team members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’m not the right person to answer a question you have, I ﻿can point you toward that person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-me&quot;&gt;Working with me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will do my best to give feedback early and often. Feedback does not mean you’ve done something wrong or bad; most of the time, I’ll want to help you improve your workflow or ask that you do something a little differently to fit company-specific culture or best practices. I ﻿like to give positive feedback too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;﻿﻿The contents of your performance reviews should never be a surprise, because it’s my job to let you know how you’re doing regularly. If at any point you don’t have a sense of how you’re doing, please ask!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also feel free to give ﻿me ﻿feedback. I’m always working to improve my management style, the work that I do, and the processes I’ve put in place. I value your knowledge and expertise, and I ﻿understand that it’s on me to create an environment where you feel comfortable sharing it. ﻿&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meetings-and-communication&quot;&gt;Meetings and communication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-schedule&quot;&gt;My schedule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My working hours are usually 9am-5pm ET. Sometimes I’ll shift my workday forward or backward by 30mins to an hour. You have access to my calendar, which I will always keep up-to-date to reflect meetings, time off, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should know that I am always “interruptible.” ﻿Please don’t ever worry about “bothering” ﻿me with a question or asking to hop on a call even when my schedule looks packed. ﻿I don’t receive Slack or email notifications outside of my workday. If you’re working while I’m not, feel free to send messages/emails/etc, and I’ll review them when I’m back online. ﻿﻿&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you receive Slack messages or emails from me outside your work hours, you’re not obligated to respond before you’re next online for work. Should I need an immediate response to something during your workday, I ﻿will make that clear. ﻿&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;11s&quot;&gt;1:1s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s likely that we’ll be in touch every day via email and/or Slack, but it’s important that we have a regularly scheduled time to catch up. Please schedule a weekly-recurring 1:1 meeting of 30 minutes (or longer, if you need it). If you need to shift our 1:1 to a different day/time, that’s fine (as long as the new meeting time is free on my calendar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll let you set the agenda for these meetings. We can talk about anything from removing blockers for your current projects to setting professional development goals, to what’s keeping you busy/happy outside of work. If you need some ideas, here are some things we can talk about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s going well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s not going well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team priorities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asking for opportunities (i.e., “I want to work on more customer-facing projects”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Career planning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asking for or giving feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brainstorming solutions for a current project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asking for resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/b0rk/status/1037186572234498048&quot;&gt;this Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;, which has other great ideas.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;worklife-balance&quot;&gt;Work/Life balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like illness, doctors’ appointments, family obligations, and home repairs might require you to take time off or move your work schedule around, and that’s okay! I ask that you keep the team informed of your availability and ﻿your calendar up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And please remember to take vacation time! I’d appreciate it if you ran vacation dates by me before booking plane tickets, etc., but I don’t “approve” or “deny” vacation requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people prefer to keep their work and personal lives mostly separate, and others enjoy sharing details about their non-work selves. If there’s anything going on in your personal life that may impact your work, please tell me as much as you’re comfortable with so that I have some context and can provide accommodations when appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! If you have questions about this README or would like me to include more information, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@katelynlemay.com&quot;&gt;drop me a line&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 25 July 2019&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I joined Hypothesis, my manager at the time sent a Manager README before my first day. It gave me a sense of what it would be like to work with him, and spelled out some expectations that we're normally required to guess at in the workplace. My README is inspired by and adapted from his— I hope you find this useful.</summary></entry></feed>